# Monique Mitchell BSN, RN Miami, FL 33186

mitchellm2016@fau.edu

813-506-3188

Highly motivated professional with proven to be interpersonal and communication skills with 6 years of nursing experience in medical surgery, oncology, ICU, cardiovascular, and emergency medicine. Communicates well within the interdisciplinary team consisting of doctors, respiratory therapists, nurses, technicians and others involved in the care transition of patients. Works well collaboratively within a team as well as an individual. Proven highly effective managerial skills over nurses and other personnel. Looking for a company that will allow me to grow as an individual and health care professional, and provide the necessary tools for me to advance within the organization.

**Education:** MSN

Nursing Admin. & Financial Leadership August 8, 2017

Florida Atlantic University

BSN, Cum Laude May 4, 2013

Florida A&M University

AA **July 2011** 

University of South Florida

### **Employment:**

Los Robles Hospital, Thousand Oaks, CA Feb 2018- May 2018 & Feb 2019-May 2019

Travel Registered Nurse-

Super Float Nurse - Surgical unit, ER, ICU, Orthopedics, Telemetry Oncology

#### **Medstar Washington Hospital**

Sept 2018- Dec 2018

Advanced Heart Failure Clinic - Travel

- Specializing in patient with ventricular assistive devices (VAD) and post heart transplant
- Competent in treating and assessing patients with VAD devices
- Generated savings for the hospital in the amount of approximately \$130,000 in 13 weeks by diligently generating a savings plan for device supplies

### **Baptist Health of South Florida**

**June 2016- February 2018** 

Registered Nurse, Emergency Department and ICU

- Oversee patients in one of the busiest Emergency departments in South Florida
- Care for ICU patients managing multiple drips, following sepsis protocols, and high acuity ICU patients
- Work collaboratively with physicians and other members of the health care team to provide the best care possible for the patients and their families
- Act as a patient advocate at all times which may consist of clarifying orders and giving opinions about the treatment plan of the patient

### **Community Health of South Florida (CHI)**

**January 2017- August 2017** 

Student Intern - (Nursing Administration) Crisis Unit

- Evaluate performance management of employees as well as the overall clinic and implement ways to improve
- Attend budget meetings and assist with the budgeting of the crisis unit
- Analyze risk and quality management such as ways to improve the safety of transportation services over the behavioral health entities of CHI
- Identify a need of the clinic and implement the interventions into practice
- Assist with staffing including scheduling and the need for additional staff
- Help with screening prospective employee applications

### Peacehealth Hospital, WA

March 2016- May 2016

Travel Registered Nurse, Medical Oncology

### James A Haley Veteran Affairs Hospital, Tampa, FL

August 2013- Feb 2016

Registered Nurse/ Charge Nurse, General Medicine/Oncology unit

- Assess on a continuum and organize care for patients on a daily and consistent basis
- Provide educational needs to patients and their families
- Act as a patient advocate
- Actively participate in governance councils such as fall prevention and staffing methodology to improve health care services on the unit and hospital wide
- Oversee other employees such as LPN's and perform leadership duties necessary of charge nurse

### Medical Weight Loss Clinic, LLC, Tampa FL

May 2013-September 2015

Registered Nurse/Supervisor

- Supervise nursing staff
- Conduct interviews/hiring and perform evaluations
- Scheduling and assist with payroll
- Initiate monthly meetings
- Provide education on weight loss and dieting
- Administer B12 injections and perform tests such as EKG
- Design plans for patients to reach their weight loss goal

# Capital Regional Medical Center, Tallahassee, FL, Nurse Extern/ Unit secretary

2012-2013

Labor and Delivery unit, Progressive Care unit, Oncology unit, Postpartum unit, Orthopedic unit Emergency Department

----

- Assist nurses in health care duties such as patients activities of daily living (ADL)
- Obtain patients vitals while informing nurses of any abnormal values
- Perform clerical duties such as filing, answering telephones, chart checks, etc.

# **Licensures and Certifications**

Registered Nurse, Florida, California Basic Life Support, 2019 Advanced Cardiac Life Support, 2019 Pediatric Advanced Life Support, 2021 NIHSS